The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
PROFESSOR: We're going to start a brand new, exciting topic,
教授：我们将开始一个崭新的，令人兴奋的话题，
dynamic programming.
动态编程。
AUDIENCE: Yes!
听众：是的！
PROFESSOR: Yeah!
教授：是的！
So exciting.
如此令人兴奋。
Actually, I am really excited because dynamic programming
实际上，我真的很兴奋，因为动态编程
is my favorite thing in the world, in algorithms.
在算法上是我最喜欢的东西。
And it's going to be the next four lectures,
接下来的四节课，
it's so exciting.
它是如此令人兴奋。
It has lots of different facets.
它具有许多不同的方面。
It's a very general, powerful design technique.
这是一种非常通用，功能强大的设计技术。
We don't talk a lot about algorithm design in this class,
在本课程中，我们不会过多地讨论算法设计，
but dynamic programming is one that's so important.
但是动态编程是如此重要。
And also takes a little while to settle in.
而且还需要一些时间才能安顿下来。
We like to injected it into you now, in 006.
我们现在想在006年将其注入您体内。
So in general, our motivation is designing new algorithms
因此，总的来说，我们的动机是设计新算法
and dynamic programming, also called DP,
和动态编程（也称为DP）
is a great way-- or a very general, powerful way
是一个好方法-或非常普遍，强大的方法
to do this.
去做这个。
It's especially good, and intended for, optimization
它特别好，并且旨在进行优化
problems, things like shortest paths.
问题，例如最短路径。
You want to find the best way to do something.
您想找到做某事的最佳方法。
Shortest path is you want to find the shortest
最短的路径是您想找到最短的路径
path, the minimum-length path.
路径，最小长度的路径。
You want to minimize, maximize something, that's
您想要最小化，最大化某些东西，那就是
an optimization problem, and typically
优化问题，通常
good algorithms to solve them involve dynamic programming.
解决它们的好的算法包括动态编程。
It's a bit of a broad statement.
这是一个广泛的声明。
You can also think of dynamic programming
您还可以想到动态编程
as a kind of exhaustive search.
作为一种详尽的搜索。
Which is usually a bad thing to do
这通常是一件坏事
because it leads to exponential time.
因为它导致指数时间。
But if you do it in a clever way, via dynamic programming,
但是，如果您通过动态编程巧妙地做到这一点，
you typically get polynomial time.
您通常会得到多项式时间。
So one perspective is that dynamic programming
因此，一种观点是动态编程
is approximately careful brute force.
大概是蛮力的。
It's kind of a funny combination.
这是一个有趣的组合。
A bit of an oxymoron.
有点矛盾。
But we take the idea of brute force, which is,
但是我们采用蛮力的想法，即
try all possibilities and you do it carefully
尝试所有可能的方法，然后仔细做
and you get it to polynomial time.
然后得到多项式时间
There are a lot of problems where essentially
本质上有很多问题
the only known polynomial time algorithm is
唯一已知的多项式时间算法是
via dynamic programming.
通过动态编程。
It doesn't always work, there's some problems
它并不总是有效，存在一些问题
where we don't think there are polynomial time algorithms,
我们认为没有多项式时间算法的地方
but when it's possible DP is a nice, sort of,
但是，DP可能很好，
general approach to it.
通用的方法。
And we're going to be talking a lot about dynamic programming.
我们将谈论很多有关动态编程的内容。
There's a lot of different ways to think about it.
有很多不同的方式来考虑它。
We'll look at a few today.
今天我们来看一些。
We're going to warm up today with some fairly easy problems
今天我们要准备解决一些相当简单的问题
that we already know how to solve,
我们已经知道如何解决，
namely computing Fibonacci numbers.
即计算斐波那契数。
It's pretty easy.
很简单
And computing shortest paths.
并计算最短路径。
And then in the next three lectures
然后在接下来的三讲中
we're going to get to more interesting examples
我们将获得更多有趣的例子
where it's pretty surprising that you can even
您甚至可以惊讶地发现
solve the problem in polynomial time.
解决多项式时间内的问题。
Probably the first burning question on your mind,
可能是您脑海中第一个亟待解决的问题，
though, is why is it called dynamic programming?
但是，为什么将其称为动态编程？
What does that even mean?
那有什么意思？
And I used to have this spiel about, well, you
我曾经有过这样的话题，好吧，你
know, programming refers to the-- I think
知道，编程是指-我认为
it's the British notion of the word,
这是英国这个词的概念，
where it's about optimization.
关于优化的地方。
Optimization in American English is something
优化美式英语
like programming in British English,
就像用英式英语编程一样
where you want to set up the program--
您要在哪里设置程序-
the schedule for your trains or something,
您的火车时间表或其他东西，
where programming comes from originally.
编程是从哪里来的
But I looked up the actual history of,
但是我查了一下，
why is it called dynamic programming.
为什么称为动态编程。
Dynamic programming was invented by a guy named Richard Bellman.
动态编程是由一个名叫Richard Bellman的人发明的。
You may have heard of Bellman in the Bellman-Ford algorithm.
您可能在Bellman-Ford算法中听说过Bellman。
So this is actually the precursor to Bellman-Ford.
因此，这实际上是Bellman-Ford的先驱。
And we're going to see Bellman-Ford come up naturally
我们将看到Bellman-Ford自然崛起
in this setting.
在这种情况下。
So here's a quote about him.
所以这是关于他的名言。
It says, Bellman explained that he
它说，贝尔曼解释说他
invented the name dynamic programming to hide the fact
发明了动态编程的名称来掩盖事实
that he was doing mathematical research.
他正在做数学研究。
He was working at this place called Rand,
他在这个叫做兰德的地方工作
and under a secretary of defense who had a pathological fear
在有病态恐惧的国防部长的领导下
and hatred for the term research.
并对研究一词表示仇恨。
So he settled on the term dynamic programming
因此，他决定使用动态编程一词
because it would be difficult to give
因为很难给
a pejorative meaning to it.
贬义的意思
And because it was something not even
而且因为那甚至没有
a congressman could object to.
国会议员可以反对。
Basically, it sounded cool.
基本上，这听起来很酷。
So that's the origin of the name dynamic programming.
这就是动态编程名称的由来。
So why is the called that?
那为什么叫那个呢？
Who knows.
谁知道。
I mean, now you know.
我的意思是，现在您知道了。
But it's not-- it's a weird term.
但这不是-这是一个奇怪的名词。
Just take it for what it is.
随便拿它是什么。
It may make some kind of sense, but--
这可能有点道理，但是-
All right.
好吧。
So we are going to start with this example of how
所以我们将从这个例子开始
to compute Fibonacci numbers.
计算斐波那契数。
And maybe before we actually start
也许在我们真正开始之前
I'm going to give you a sneak peak of what
我要给你一个偷偷摸摸的高峰
you can think of dynamic programming as.
您可以将动态编程视为。
And this equation, so to speak, is
可以说，这个等式是
going to change throughout today's lecture.
在今天的演讲中将会有所改变。
In the end we'll settle on a sort
最后，我们将解决一个问题
of more accurate perspective.
更准确的视角。
The basic idea of dynamic programming
动态编程的基本思想
is to take a problem, split it into subproblems,
是要解决一个问题，将其分解为子问题，
solve those subproblems, and reuse the solutions
解决这些子问题，然后重用解决方案
to your subproblems.
您的子问题。
It's like a lesson in recycling.
这就像回收中的一课。
So we'll see that in Fibonacci numbers.
因此，我们将在斐波纳契数中看到这一点。
So you remember Fibonacci numbers, right?
所以您还记得斐波那契数，对吗？
The number of rabbits you have on day n, if they reproduce.
您在第n天繁殖的兔子数量。
We've mentioned them before, we're talking about AVL trees,
我们之前提到过它们，我们在谈论AVL树，
I think.
我认为。
So this is the usual-- you can think
所以这是平常的-你可以想到
of it as a recursive definition or recurrence on Fibonacci
作为递归定义或斐波那契上的递归
numbers.
数字。
It's the definition of what the nth Fibonacci number is.
这是第n个斐波那契数的定义。
So let's suppose our goal-- an algorithmic problem is,
因此，假设我们的目标是一个算法问题，
compute the nth Fibonacci number.
计算第n个斐波那契数。
And I'm going to assume here that that fits in a word.
我将在这里假设一个词。
And so basic arithmetic, addition,
基本算术，加法，
whatever's constant time per operation.
每次操作的固定时间是多少。
So how do we do it?
那么我们该怎么做呢？
You all know how to do it.
你们都知道该怎么做。
Anyways-- but I'm going to give you the dynamic programming
无论如何-但我将为您提供动态编程
perspective on things.
对事物的看法。
So this will seem kind of obvious,
所以这看起来很明显，
but it is-- we're going to apply exactly the same principles
但这是-我们将应用完全相同的原理
that we will apply over and over in dynamic programming.
我们将一遍又一遍地应用于动态编程中。
But here it's in a very familiar setting.
但是这里的环境非常熟悉。
So we're going to start with the naive recursive algorithm.
因此，我们将从朴素的递归算法开始。
And that is, if you want to compute the nth Fibonacci
也就是说，如果您要计算第n个斐波那契
number, you check whether you're in the base case.
数字，请检查您是否在基本情况下。
I'm going to write it this way.
我要这样写。
So f is just our return value.
所以f只是我们的返回值。
You'll see why I write it this way in a moment.
您很快就会明白为什么我要这样写。
Then you return f.
然后返回f。
In the base case it's 1, otherwise
在基本情况下为1，否则为
you recursively call Fibonacci of n minus 1.
您递归地调用n减1的斐波那契。
You recursively call Fibonacci of n minus 2.
您递归地调用n减2的斐波那契。
Add them together, return that.
将它们加在一起，返回。
This is a correct algorithm.
这是正确的算法。
Is it a good algorithm?
这是一个好的算法吗？
No.
没有。
It's very bad.
这很糟糕。
Exponential time.
指数时间。
How do we know it's exponential time,
我们怎么知道现在是指数时间
other than from experience?
除了经验之外？
Well, we can write the running time as recurrence.
好吧，我们可以将运行时间写为递归。
T of n represents the time to compute the nth Fibonacci
n的T代表计算第n个斐波那契的时间
number.
数。
How can I write the recurrence?
如何写复发？
You're gonna throwback to the early lectures, divide
您将退回到早期的讲座，分开
and conquer.
并征服。
I hear whispers.
我听到耳语。
Yeah?
是啊
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE].
听众：[听不清]。
PROFESSOR: Yeah.
教授：是的。
T of n minus 1 plus t of n minus 2 plus constant.
T的n减1加n的t减2加常数。
I don't know how many you have by now.
我不知道你现在有多少。
So to create the nth Fibonacci number
因此要创建第n个斐波那契数
we have to compute the n minus first Fibonacci number,
我们必须计算n减去第一个斐波那契数，
and the n minus second Fibonacci number.
和n减去第二斐波那契数。
That's these two recursions.
这就是这两个递归。
And then we take constant time otherwise.
然后，我们花费固定的时间。
We do constant number of additions, comparisons.
我们进行固定数量的加法，比较。
Return all these operations-- take constant time.
返回所有这些操作-花费固定的时间。
So that's a recurrence.
所以这是重复发生的。
How do we solve this recurrence?
我们如何解决这种复发？
Well one way is to see this is the Fibonacci recurrence.
很好的一种方法就是看这是斐波那契复发。
So it's the same thing.
所以是同一回事。
There's this plus whatever.
有这个加什么。
But in particular, this is at least the nth Fibonacci number.
但特别是，这至少是第n个斐波那契数。
And if you know Fibonacci stuff, that's
如果你知道斐波那契的东西，那就是
about the golden ratio to the nth power.
关于黄金比例与n次方的关系。
Which is bad.
不好
We had a similar recurrence in AVL trees.
我们在AVL树中也有类似的复发情况。
And so another way to solve it-- it's
解决问题的另一种方法是
just good review-- say, oh well, that's
很好的评价-说，哦，那是
at least 2 times t of n minus 2.
至少是n减去2的t的2倍。
Because it's going to be monotone.
因为它将是单调的。
The bigger n is, the more work you have to do.
n越大，您要做的工作就越多。
Because to do the nth thing you have
因为要做第n件事
to do the n minus first thing.
做n减第一件事。
So we could just reduce t of n minus 1 to t of n minus 2.
所以我们可以将n的t减1减为n的t减2。
That will give us a lower bound.
这将给我们一个下限。
And now these two terms-- now this is sort of an easy thing.
现在，这两个术语-现在这很容易。
You see that you're multiplying by 2 each time.
您会看到每次乘以2。
You're subtracting 2 from n each time.
每次从n中减去2。
How many times can I subtract 2 from n?
我可以从n中减去2次？
N/2 times, before I get down to a constant.
N / 2次，直到我趋于恒定。
And so this is equal to 2 to the n over 2--
所以这等于2等于n的2
I mean, times some constant, which
我的意思是，乘以一些常数，
is what you get in the base case.
这就是基本情况。
So I guess I should say theta.
所以我想我应该说theta。
This thing is theta that.
这个东西就是那个。
OK.
好。
So it's at least that big.
因此，至少有那么大。
And the right constant is phi.
正确的常数是phi。
And the base of the exponent.
和指数的基础。
OK.
好。
So that's a bad algorithm.
所以这是一个不好的算法。
We all know it's a bad algorithm.
我们都知道这是一个不好的算法。
But I'm going to give you a general approach for making
但我将为您提供一种通用的制作方法
bad algorithms like this good.
像这样好的算法。
And that general approach is called memoization.
这种通用方法称为记忆。
We'll go over here.
我们将在这里过去。
And this is a technique of dynamic programming.
这是一种动态编程技术。
So I'm going to call this the memoized dynamic programming
所以我将其称为记忆化的动态编程
algorithm.
算法。
So did I settle on using memo in the notes?
所以我决定在笔记中使用备忘录吗？
Yeah.
是的
The idea is simple.
这个想法很简单。
Whenever we compute a Fibonacci number
每当我们计算斐波那契数
we put it in a dictionary.
我们把它放在字典里。
And then when we need to compute the nth Fibonacci
然后当我们需要计算第n个斐波那契
number we check, is it already in the dictionary?
我们检查的数字，已经在字典中了吗？
Did we already solve this problem?
我们已经解决了这个问题吗？
If so, return that answer.
如果是这样，请返回该答案。
Otherwise, computer it.
否则，将其计算机化。
You'll see the transformation is very simple.
您会看到转换非常简单。
OK.
好。
These two lines are identical to these two lines.
这两行与这两行相同。
So you can see how the transformation
所以你可以看到如何转变
works in general.
一般工作。
You could do this with any recursive algorithm.
您可以使用任何递归算法来做到这一点。
The memoization transformation on that algorithm--
该算法的记忆转换-
which is, we initially make an empty dictionary called memo.
也就是说，我们最初制作了一个空的字典，称为备忘。
And before we actually do the computation we say,
在实际进行计算之前，我们说
well, check whether this version of the Fibonacci problem,
好吧，检查这个版本的斐波那契问题，
computing f of n, is already in our dictionary.
计算n的f已在我们的字典中。
So if that key is already in the dictionary,
因此，如果该键已经在字典中，
we return the corresponding value in the dictionary.
我们在字典中返回相应的值。
And then once we've computed the nth Fibonacci number,
然后，一旦我们计算了第n个斐波那契数，
if we bothered to do this, if this didn't apply,
如果我们不愿意这样做，如果不适用，
then we store it in the memo table.
然后将其存储在备注表中。
So we say well, if you ever need to compute f of n again,
所以我们说得好，如果您再次需要计算n的f，
here it is.
这里是。
And then we return that value.
然后我们返回该值。
So this is a general procedure.
因此，这是一个一般步骤。
It can apply to any recursive algorithm
它可以应用于任何递归算法
with no side effects I guess, technically.
从技术上讲，我认为没有副作用。
And it turns out, this makes the algorithm efficient.
事实证明，这使算法高效。
Now there's a lot of ways to see why it's efficient.
现在，有很多方法可以查看其为何有效。
In general, maybe it's helpful to think about the recursion
通常，考虑递归可能会有所帮助
tree.
树。
So if you want to compute fn in the old algorithm,
因此，如果您想用旧算法计算fn，
we compute fn minus 1 and fn minus two
我们计算fn减1和fn减2
completely separately.
完全分开。
To compute fn minus 1 we compute fn minus 2 and fn minus 3.
要计算fn负1，我们计算fn负2和fn负3。
To compute fn minus 2 we compute fn minus 3 and fn minus 4.
要计算fn负2，我们计算fn负3和fn负4。
And so on.
等等。
And you can see why that's exponential in n.
您会看到为什么在n中是指数的。
Because we're only decrementing n by one or two each time.
因为我们每次只将n减一或二。
But then you observe, hey, these fn minus 3's are the same.
但是您会发现，嘿，这些fn减3是相同的。
I should really only have to compute them once.
我真的应该只计算一次。
And that's what we're doing here.
这就是我们在这里所做的。
The first time you call fn minus 3, you do work.
第一次调用fn减3，就可以工作。
But once it's done and you go over to this other recursive
但是一旦完成，您就可以进行其他递归
call, this will just get cut off.
电话，这将被切断。
There's no tree here.
这里没有树。
Here we might have some recursive calling.
在这里，我们可能会有一些递归调用。
Here we won't, because it's already in the memo table.
在这里我们不会，因为它已经在备忘录表中了。
In fact, this already happens with fn minus 2.
实际上，这已经在fn减2时发生。
This whole tree disappears because fn minus 2
这整个树消失了，因为fn减2
has already been done.
已经完成了。
OK.
好。
So it's clear why it improves things.
因此很明显为什么它可以改善性能。
So in fact you can argue that this call will be free
因此，实际上您可以争辩说此通话将是免费的
because you already did the work in here.
因为您已经在这里完成了工作。
But I want to give you a very particular way of thinking
但是我想给你一个非常特殊的思考方式
about why this is efficient, which is following.
关于为什么这样高效的问题，接下来是。
So you could write down a recurrence for the running time
这样您就可以记下运行时间的重复周期
here.
这里。
But in some sense recurrences aren't quite the right way
但是从某种意义上讲，复发并不是正确的方法
of thinking about this because recursion
考虑这一点，因为递归
is kind of a rare thing.
是一件罕见的事情。
If you're calling Fibonacci of some value, k,
如果您呼叫某个值的斐波那契，k，
you're only going to make recursive calls the first time
您只会在第一时间进行递归调用
you call Fibonacci of k.
您称k为斐波那契。
Because henceforth, you've put it
因为从此以后，您已经把它
in the memo table you will not recurse.
在备忘录表中，您将不会递归。
So you can think of there being two versions
所以你可以想到有两个版本
of calling Fibonacci of k.
称为k的斐波那契。
There's the first time, which is the non-memoized version that
这是第一次，这是非记忆版
does recursion-- does some work.
进行递归-做一些工作。
And then every time henceforth you're
然后从此以后每次
doing memoized calls of Fibonacci of k,
对k的斐波那契进行记忆化调用，
and those cost constant time.
而那些花费固定的时间。
So the memoized calls cost constant time.
因此，已记录的呼叫要花费固定的时间。
So we can think of them as basically free.
因此我们可以认为它们基本上是免费的。
That's when you call Fibonacci of n minus 2,
那就是您将n减为2的斐波那契
because that's a memoized call, you really
因为那是个回忆电话，您真的
don't pay anything for it.
不要为此付出任何代价。
I mean, you're already paying constant time
我的意思是，您已经在支付固定时间了
to do addition and whatever.
做加法等等。
So you don't have to worry about the time.
因此，您不必担心时间。
There's no recursion here.
这里没有递归。
And then what we care about is that the number
然后我们关心的是数字
of non-memorized calls, which is the first time you
非记忆电话，这是您第一次
call Fibonacci of k, is n.
称k的斐波那契为n。
No theta is even necessary.
甚至没有θ是必要的。
We are going to call Fibonacci of 1.
我们将斐波那契定为1。
At some point we're going to call Fibonacci of 2
在某个时候，我们将斐波那契定为2
at some point, and the original call is Fibonacci of n.
在某个时候，最初的电话是n的斐波那契。
All of those things will be called at some point.
所有这些事情都会在某个时候被调用。
That's pretty easy to see.
这很容易看到。
But in particular, certainly at most this,
但尤其是，当然，至多，
we never call Fibonacci of n plus 1
我们从不叫n加1的斐波那契
to compute Fibonacci of n.
计算n的斐波那契
So it's at most n calls.
因此最多只能进行n次通话。
Indeed it will be exactly n calls that are not memoized.
实际上，恰好是n个未记忆的调用。
Those ones we have to pay for.
那些我们必须付费的东西。
How much do we have to pay?
我们要付多少钱？
Well, if you don't count the recursion-- which
好吧，如果您不计算递归-
is what this recurrence does-- if you ignore
这就是重复发生的事情-如果您忽略
recursion then the total amount of work done here is constant.
递归，则此处完成的工作总量是恒定的。
So I will say the non-recursive work per call is constant.
因此，我将说每次调用的非递归工作是恒定的。
And therefore I claim that the running time is
因此，我声称运行时间为
constant-- I'm sorry, is linear.
常量-很抱歉，是线性的。
Constant would be pretty amazing.
常数将是惊人的。
This is actually not the best algorithm-- as an aside.
顺便说一句，这实际上并不是最佳算法。
The best algorithm for computing the nth Fibonacci number
计算第n个斐波那契数的最佳算法
uses log n arithmetic operations.
使用log n算术运算。
So you can do better, but if you want
这样您可以做得更好，但是如果您愿意
to see that you should take 6046.
看到你应该服用6046。
OK.
好。
We're just going to get to linear today, which
今天我们要线性化，
is a lot better than exponential.
比指数好得多。
So why linear?
那么为什么线性？
Because there's n non-memoize calls, and each of them
因为有n个非记忆呼叫，每个呼叫
cost constant.
成本常数。
So it's the product of those two numbers.
这是这两个数字的乘积。
This is an important idea.
这是一个重要的想法。
And it's so important I'm going to write it
这很重要，我要写出来
down again in a slightly more general framework.
在更一般的框架中再次下降。
In general, in dynamic programming--
通常，在动态编程中-
I didn't say why it's called memoization.
我没有说为什么称之为记忆。
The idea is you have this memo pad where
这个想法是你有这个记事本
you write down all your scratch work.
您写下所有的草稿工作。
That's this memo dictionary.
那是这个备忘录字典。
And to memoize is to write down on your memo pad.
记住就是在记事本上写下来。
I didn't make it up.
我没有弥补。
Another crazy term.
另一个疯狂的名词。
It means remember.
这意味着要记住。
And then you remember all the solutions that you've done.
然后，您会记住已完成的所有解决方案。
And then you reuse those solutions.
然后，您可以重复使用这些解决方案。
Now these solutions are not really a solution
现在这些解决方案并不是真正的解决方案
to the problem that I care about.
我关心的问题。
The problem I care about is computing the nth Fibonacci
我关心的问题是计算第n个斐波那契
number.
数。
To get there I had to compute other Fibonacci numbers.
为了到达那里，我不得不计算其他斐波那契数。
Why?
为什么？
Because I had a recursive formulation.
因为我有递归公式。
This is not always the way to solve a problem.
这并不总是解决问题的方法。
But usually when you're solving something
但是通常在您解决问题时
you can split it into parts, into subproblems, we call them.
您可以将其分为多个部分，再分为子问题，我们称它们为。
They're not always of the same flavor
它们并不总是一样
as your original goal problem, but there's
作为您最初的目标问题，但是有
some kind of related parts.
一些相关的部分。
And this is the big challenge in designing a dynamic program,
这是设计动态程序的巨大挑战，
is to figure out what are the subproblems.
找出什么是子问题。
Let's say, the first thing I want
比方说，我要的第一件事
to know about a dynamic program, is what are the subproblems.
要了解动态程序，子问题是什么。
Somehow they are designed to help solve your actual problem.
它们旨在以某种方式帮助您解决实际问题。
And the idea of memoization is, once you solve a subproblem,
记忆的想法是，一旦解决了一个子问题，
write down the answer.
写下答案。
If you ever need to solve that same problem again
如果您需要再次解决相同的问题
you reuse the answer.
您重复使用答案。
So that is the core idea.
这就是核心思想。
And so in this sense dynamic programming
所以从这个意义上讲，动态编程
is essentially recursion plus memoization.
本质上是递归加记忆。
And so in this case these are the subproblems.
因此，在这种情况下，这些是子问题。
Fibonacci of 1 through Fibonacci of n.
1的斐波那契到n的斐波那契。
The one we care about is Fibonacci of n.
我们关心的是n的斐波那契。
But to get there we solve these other subproblems.
但是到那里我们可以解决其他子问题。
In all cases, if this is the situation-- so
在所有情况下，如果是这种情况，那么
for any dynamic program, the running time
对于任何动态程序，运行时间
is going to be equal to the number of different subproblems
将等于不同子问题的数量
you might have to solve, or that you do solve,
您可能必须解决，或者确实要解决，
times the amount of time you spend per subproblem.
是每个子问题花费的时间的两倍。
OK.
好。
In this situation we had n subproblems.
在这种情况下，我们有n个子问题。
And for each of them we spent constant time.
对于他们每个人，我们都花了恒定的时间。
And when I measure the time per subproblem
当我测量每个子问题的时间时
which, in the Fibonacci case I claim is constant,
在我声称的斐波那契案例中，它是恒定的，
I ignore recursive calls.
我忽略了递归调用。
That's the key.
那是关键。
We don't have to solve recurrences
我们不必解决重复问题
with dynamic programming.
动态编程。
Yay.
好极了。
No recurrences necessary.
无需重复。
OK.
好。
Don't count recursions.
不计算递归。
Obviously, don't count memoized recursions.
显然，不要计算已记录的递归。
The reason is, I only need to count them once.
原因是，我只需要计数一次。
After the first time I do it, it's free.
我第一次这样做后，它是免费的。
So I count how many different subproblems do I need to do?
因此，我需要计算多少个不同的子问题？
These are they going to be the expensive recursions where
这些将是昂贵的递归
I do work, I do some amount of work,
我会工作，我会做一些工作，
but I don't count the recursions because otherwise I'd
但我不计算递归，否则我会
be double counting.
重复计算。
I only want to count each subproblem once,
我只想对每个子问题计算一次，
and then this will solve it.
然后就可以解决。
So a simple idea.
所以一个简单的想法。
In general, dynamic programming is a super simple idea.
通常，动态编程是一个非常简单的想法。
It's nothing fancy.
没什么好看的。
It's basically just memoization.
基本上只是记忆。
There is one extra trick we're going to pull out,
我们要抽出另外一招，
but that's the idea.
但这就是想法。
All right.
好吧。
Let me tell you another perspective.
让我告诉您另一个观点。
This is the one maybe most commonly taught.
这可能是最常教授的一种。
Is to think of-- but I'm not a particular fan of it.
值得一提的是-但我并不特别喜欢它。
I really like memoization.
我真的很喜欢记忆
I think it's a simple idea.
我认为这是一个简单的想法。
And as long as you remember this formula here,
只要您记得这里的公式，
it's really easy to work with.
真的很容易使用。
But some people like to think of it this way.
但是有些人喜欢这样想。
And so you can pick whichever way you find most intuitive.
因此，您可以选择最直观的方式。
Instead of thinking of a recursive algorithm, which
而不是考虑递归算法，
in some sense starts at the top of what you want to solve
在某种意义上说，从您要解决的问题的顶部开始
and works its way down, you could do the reverse.
然后逐步下降，您可以进行相反的操作。
You could start at the bottom and work your way up.
您可以从底部开始，然后逐步提高。
And this is probably how you normally
这可能就是你平时的样子
think about computing Fibonacci numbers
考虑计算斐波纳契数
or how you learned it before.
或您之前的学习方法。
I'm going to write it in a slightly funny way.
我将以一种稍微有趣的方式来编写它。
The point I want to make is that the transformation
我想指出的是，转型
I'm doing from the naive recursive algorithm,
我是从朴素的递归算法做的，
to the memoized algorithm, to the bottom-up algorithm
记忆算法，自底向上算法
is completely automated.
完全自动化。
I'm not thinking, I'm just doing.
我不在考虑，我只是在做。
OK.
好。
It's easy.
这很容易。
This code is exactly the same as this code
该代码与该代码完全相同
and as that code, except I replaced n by k.
和那样的代码，除了我用k代替n。
Just because I needed a couple of different n values here.
只是因为我在这里需要几个不同的n值。
Or I want to iterate over n values.
或者我想遍历n个值。
And then there's this stuff around that code
然后在代码周围有这个东西
which is just formulaic.
这只是公式化的。
A little bit of thought goes into this for loop,
有点想法进入这个循环，
but that's it.
就是这样。
OK.
好。
This does exactly the same thing as the memoized algorithm.
这与记忆算法完全相同。
Maybe it takes a little bit of thinking
也许需要一点思考
to realize, if you unroll all the recursion that's happening
意识到，如果展开所有正在发生的递归
here and just write it out sequentially,
在这里，然后按顺序写出来，
this is exactly what's happening.
这正是正在发生的事情。
This code does exactly the same additions, exactly
这段代码做了完全相同的添加，
the same computations as this.
与此相同的计算。
The only difference is how you get there.
唯一的区别是您到达那里的方式。
Here we're using a loop, here we're using recursion.
这里我们使用循环，这里我们使用递归。
But the same things happen in the same order.
但是相同的事情以相同的顺序发生。
It's really no difference between the code.
两者之间的代码确实没有区别。
This code's probably going to be more efficient practice
这段代码可能会更有效
because you don't make function calls so much.
因为您不会进行太多函数调用。
In fact I made a little mistake here.
实际上，我在这里犯了一个小错误。
This is not a function call, it's
这不是函数调用，而是
just a lookup into a table.
只是查表。
Here I'm using a hash table to be simple,
在这里，我使用一个哈希表来简化操作，
but of course you could use an array.
但是您当然可以使用数组。
But they're both constant time with good hashing.
但是他们都是时间稳定且哈希值很高。
All right.
好吧。
So is it clear what this is doing?
很清楚这是在做什么吗？
I think so.
我认同。
I think I made a little typo.
我想我打错了字。
So we have to compute-- oh, another typo.
所以我们必须计算-哦，另一个错字。
We have to compute f1 up to fn, which in python is that.
我们必须计算f1到fn，在python中就是这样。
And we compute it exactly how we used to.
而且我们可以像以前一样精确地进行计算。
Except now, instead of recursing,
除了现在，不再重复
I know that when I'm computing the k Fibonacci number-- man.
我知道，当我计算k斐波那契数时，老兄。
So many typos.
这么多错别字。
AUDIENCE: [LAUGHTER]
观众：[笑声]
PROFESSOR: You guys are laughing.
教授：你们在笑。
When I compute the kth Fibonacci number
当我计算第k个斐波那契数
I know that I've already computed the previous two.
我知道我已经计算了前两个。
Why?
为什么？
Because I'm doing them in increasing order.
因为我正在按递增顺序进行操作。
Nothing fancy.
没有什么花哨。
Then I can just do this and the solutions
然后我就可以做到这一点和解决方案
will just be waiting there.
会在那里等。
If they work, I'd get a key error.
如果它们起作用，我将得到一个关键错误。
So I'd know that there's a bug.
所以我知道有一个错误。
But in fact, I won't get a key error.
但实际上，我不会遇到关键错误。
I will have always computed these things already.
我会一直计算这些东西。
Then I store it in my table.
然后将其存储在我的表中。
Then I iterate.
然后我迭代。
Eventually I've solved all the subproblems, f1 through fn.
最终，我解决了所有子问题，从f1到fn。
And the one I cared about was the nth one.
我关心的是第n个。
OK.
好。
So straightforward.
如此简单。
I do this because I don't really want
我这样做是因为我真的不想要
to have to go through this transformation
必须经历这种转变
for every single problem we do.
对于我们遇到的每个问题。
I'm doing it in Fibonacci because it's super easy
我在斐波那契做，因为它非常容易
to write the code out explicitly.
明确地写出代码。
But you can do it for all of the dynamic programs
但是您可以对所有动态程序执行此操作
that we cover in the next four lectures.
我们将在接下来的四个讲座中介绍。
OK.
好。
I'm going to give you now the general case.
现在，我将为您提供一般情况。
This was the special Fibonacci version.
这是特殊的斐波那契版本。
In general, the bottom-up does exactly the same computation
通常，自下而上的计算完全相同
as the memoized version.
作为备忘录版本。
And what we're doing is actually a topological sort
而我们正在做的实际上是一种拓扑
of the subproblem dependency DAG.
子问题依赖项DAG的定义。
So in this case, the dependency DAG is very simple.
因此，在这种情况下，依赖项DAG非常简单。
In order to compute-- I'll do it backwards.
为了进行计算，我将向后进行。
In order to compute fn, I need to know fn minus 1
为了计算fn，我需要知道fn减1
and fn minus 2.
和fn减2。
If I know those I can compute fn.
如果我知道这些，我可以计算fn。
Then there's fn minus 3, which is
然后是fn减3，即
necessary to compute this one, and that one, and so on.
计算这个和那个，等等的必要。
So you see what this DAG looks like.
因此，您将看到此DAG的外观。
Now, I've drawn it conveniently so
现在，我已经方便地绘制了
all the edges go left to right.
所有边缘从左到右。
So this is a topological order from left to right.
因此，这是从左到右的拓扑顺序。
And so I just need to do f1, f2, up to fn in order.
因此，我只需要依次执行f1，f2到fn。
Usually it's totally obvious what order
通常很明显什么顺序
to solve the subproblems in.
解决子问题。
But in general, what you should have in mind
但总的来说，您应该牢记
is that we are doing a topological sort.
是我们正在做拓扑排序。
Here we just did it in our heads because it's so easy.
在这里，我们只是在脑海中做到了，因为它是如此简单。
And usually it's so easy.
通常这很容易。
It's just a for loop.
这只是一个for循环。
Nothing fancy.
没有什么花哨。
All right.
好吧。
I'm missing an arrow.
我错过了一支箭。
All right.
好吧。
Let's do something a little more interesting, shall we?
让我们做一些更有趣的事情吧？
All right.
好吧。
One thing you can do from this bottom-up perspective
从此自下而上的角度来看，您可以做一件事
is you can save space.
是您可以节省空间。
Storage space in the algorithm.
算法中的存储空间。
We don't usually worry about space in this class,
我们通常不用担心此类的空间，
but it matters in reality.
但实际上很重要
So here we're building a table size,
所以这里我们要建立一个表格大小
n, but in fact we really only need
n，但实际上我们只需要
to remember the last two values.
记住最后两个值。
So you could just store the last two values,
这样您就可以存储最后两个值，
and each time you make a new one delete the oldest.
每次您制作一个新的，都会删除最旧的。
so by thinking a little bit here you
所以在这里想一想
realize you only need constant space.
意识到您只需要恒定的空间。
Still linear time, but constant space.
时间仍然是线性的，但空间不变。
And that's often the case.
通常就是这种情况。
From the bottom-up perspective you
从下至上的角度来看，
see what you really need to store,
看看您真正需要存储什么，
what you need to keep track of.
您需要跟踪的内容。
All right.
好吧。
I guess another nice thing about this perspective
我猜想这个观点还有另一个好处
is, the running time is totally obvious.
是，运行时间是完全显而易见的。
This is clearly constant time.
这显然是恒定的时间。
So this is clearly linear time.
因此，这显然是线性时间。
Whereas, in this memoized algorithm
而在此记忆算法中
you have to think about, when's it
你必须考虑，什么时候
going to be memoized, when is it not?
要被记住，什么时候不被记住？
I still like this perspective because, with this rule,
我仍然喜欢这种观点，因为按照这个规则，
just multiply a number of subproblems
只是乘以一些子问题
by time per subproblem, you get the answer.
通过每个子问题的时间，您会得到答案。
But it's a little less obvious than code like this.
但这并不比这样的代码明显。
So choose however you like to think about it.
因此，请选择您想考虑的内容。
All right.
好吧。
We move onto shortest paths.
我们走上最短的道路。
So I'm again, as usual, thinking about single-source shortest
所以我像往常一样再次考虑最短的单一来源
paths.
路径。
So we want to compute the shortest pathway from s
所以我们要计算的最短路径
to v for all v. OK.
到v代表所有v。
I'd like to write this initially as a naive recursive algorithm,
我想最初将其编写为天真的递归算法，
which I can then memoize, which I can then bottom-upify.
然后我可以记住，然后我可以自下而上。
I just made that up.
我只是编造的。
So how could I write this as a naive recursive algorithm?
那么我怎么能把它写成一个朴素的递归算法呢？
It's not so obvious.
这不是很明显。
But first I'm going to tell you how, just as an oracle tells
但是首先，我将告诉您如何，就像甲骨文告诉您的那样
you, here's what you should do.
你，这是你应该做的。
But then we're going to think about-- go back, step back.
但是接下来我们要考虑-回去，退后一步。
Actually, it's up to you.
实际上，这取决于您。
I could tell you the answer and then
我可以告诉你答案，然后
we could figure out how we got there,
我们可以弄清楚如何到达那里，
or we could just figure out the answer.
或者我们可以找出答案。
Preferences?
首选项？
Figure it out.
想办法。
All right.
好吧。
Good.
好。
No divine inspiration allowed.
不允许有上帝的启示。
So let me give you a tool.
所以让我给你一个工具。
The tool is guessing.
该工具正在猜测。
This may sound silly, but it's a very powerful tool.
这听起来很愚蠢，但这是一个非常强大的工具。
The general idea is, suppose you don't know something
一般的想法是，假设你不知道什么
but you'd like to know it.
但您想知道。
So what's the answer to this question?
那么这个问题的答案是什么？
I don't know.
我不知道。
Man, I really want a cushion.
老兄，我真的很想坐垫。
How am I going to answer the question?
我要如何回答这个问题？
Guess.
猜测。
OK?
好？
AUDIENCE: [LAUGHTER]
观众：[笑声]
PROFESSOR: It's a tried and tested method
教授：这是一种久经考验的方法
for solving any problem.
解决任何问题。
I'm kind of belaboring the point here.
我有点be惜这里。
The algorithmic concept is, don't just try any guess.
算法的概念是，不要只是尝试任何猜测。
Try them all.
尝试所有。
OK?
好？
AUDIENCE: [LAUGHTER]
观众：[笑声]
PROFESSOR: Also pretty simple.
教授：也很简单。
I said dynamic programming was simple.
我说动态编程很简单。
OK.
好。
Try all guesses.
尝试所有猜测。
This is central to the dynamic programming.
这对于动态编程至关重要。
I know it sounds obvious, but if I want to fix my equation here,
我知道这听起来很明显，但是如果我想在这里修正方程式，
dynamic programming is roughly recursion plus memoization.
动态编程大致是递归加记忆。
This should really be, plus guessing.
这确实应该是，加上猜测。
Memoization, which is obvious, guessing which is obvious,
记忆很明显，猜测很明显，
are the central concepts to dynamic programming.
是动态编程的核心概念。
I'm trying to make it sound easy because usually people
我正在尝试使其听起来很简单，因为通常人们
have trouble with dynamic programming.
动态编程遇到麻烦。
It is easy.
这很容易。
Try all the guesses.
尝试所有的猜测。
That's something a computer can do great.
这是计算机可以做的出色的事情。
This is the brute force part.
这是蛮力部分。
OK.
好。
But we're going to do it carefully.
但是，我们将谨慎进行。
Not that carefully.
没那么仔细。
I mean, we're just trying all the guesses.
我的意思是，我们只是在尝试所有猜测。
Take the best one.
拿最好的一个。
That's kind of important that we can choose one
这很重要，我们可以选择一个
to be called best.
被称为最佳。
That's why dynamic programming is
这就是为什么动态编程是
good for optimization problems.
对优化问题有好处。
You want to maximize something, minimize something,
您想最大化某些东西，最小化某些东西，
you try them all and then you can forget about all of them
你尝试所有的东西，然后你就可以忘记所有的东西
and just reduce it down to one thing which
并将其简化为一件事
is the best one, or a best one.
是最好的，还是最好的。
OK.
好。
So now I want you to try to apply
所以现在我要你尝试申请
this principle to shortest paths.
这条最短路径的原则。
Now I'm going to draw a picture which may help.
现在，我要画一幅画可能会有所帮助。
We have the source, s, we have some vertex,
我们有源s，有一些顶点，
v. We'd like to find the shortest--
v。我们想找到最短的-
a shortest path from s to v.
从s到v的最短路径。
Suppose I want to know what this shortest path is.
假设我想知道这条最短的路径是什么。
Suppose this was it.
假设是这样。
You have an idea already?
你有个主意吗？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: What you could do is you could look at everywhere
观众：您可以做的是随处可见
you can go from s.
你可以从s去。
[INAUDIBLE] shortest path of each of those notes.
[音符]每个音符的最短路径。
PROFESSOR: Good.
教授：很好。
So I can look at all the places I could go from s,
所以我可以查看我可以从s到达的所有地方，
and then look at the shortest paths from there to v.
然后查看从那里到v的最短路径。
So we could call this s prime.
因此，我们可以称其为素数。
So here's the idea.
所以这就是想法。
There's some hypothetical shortest path.
有一些假设的最短路径。
I don't know where it goes first,
我不知道先去哪
so I will guess where it goes first.
所以我猜猜它先去哪里。
I know the first edge must be one
我知道第一个优势一定是
of the outgoing edges from s.
从s传出的边缘。
I don't know which one.
我不知道是哪一个。
Try them all.
尝试所有。
Very simple idea.
很简单的主意。
Then from each of those, if somehow I
然后从每个这些，如果我以某种方式
can compute the shortest path from there to v,
可以计算从那里到v的最短路径，
just do that and take the best choice
只要做到这一点，并采取最佳选择
for what that first edge was.
对于第一个优势是什么。
So this would be the guess first edge approach.
因此，这将是猜测的第一个优势方法。
It's a very good idea.
这是一个很好的主意。
Not quite the one I wanted because unfortunately
不完全是我想要的那个，因为不幸的是
that changes s.
改变s。
And so this would work, it would just
所以这将起作用，它将只是
be slightly less efficient if I'm
如果我的效率较低
solving single-source shortest paths.
解决单一来源最短路径。
So I'm going to tweak that idea slightly
所以我要稍微调整一下这个想法
by guessing the last edge instead of the first edge.
通过猜测最后一个边缘而不是第一个边缘。
They're really equivalent.
它们实际上是等效的。
If I was doing this I'd essentially
如果我这样做的话，我基本上会
be solving a single-target shortest paths,
解决单一目标的最短路径，
which we talked about before.
我们之前讨论过。
So I'm going to draw the same picture.
因此，我将绘制相同的图片。
I want to get to v. I'm going to guess the last edge,
我要诉诸v。我要猜测最后一个优势，
call it uv.
称之为uv。
I know it's one of the incoming edges to v-- unless s equals v,
我知道这是v的传入边之一-除非s等于v，
then there's a special case.
然后有一个特例。
As long as this path has length of at least 1,
只要该路径的长度至少为1，
there's some last edge.
还有一些最后的优势。
What is it?
它是什么？
I don't know.
我不知道。
Guess.
猜测。
Guess all the possible incoming edges to v, and then
猜测所有可能的传入边到v，然后
recursively compute the shortest path from s to u.
递归计算从s到u的最短路径。
And then add on the edge v.
然后添加边缘v。
OK.
好。
So what is this shortest path?
那么，这条最短的路径是什么？
It's delta of s comma u, which looks the same.
它是逗号的增量，看起来一样。
It's another subproblem that I want to solve.
这是我要解决的另一个子问题。
There's v subproblems here I care about. .
我关心的是这里的v个子问题。 。
So that's good.
这样很好。
I take that.
我接受
I add on the weight of the edge uv.
我增加了边缘uv的重量。
And that should hopefully give me delta of s comma v.
希望这能给我s逗号v的增量。
Well, if I was lucky and I guessed the right choice of u.
好吧，如果我很幸运，我猜到你的选择是正确的。
In reality, I'm not lucky.
实际上，我并不幸运。
So I have to minimize over all edges uv.
因此，我必须在所有方面使uv最小化。
So this is the-- we're minimizing
这就是我们正在将
over the choice of u.
在你的选择上
V is already given here.
V已经在这里给出。
So I take the minimum over all edges of the shortest
所以我在最短的所有边上取最小值
path from s to u, plus the weight of the edge uv.
从s到u的路径，加上边缘uv的权重。
That should give me the shortest path because this gave me
那应该给我最短的路，因为这给了我
the shortest path from s to u.
从s到u的最短路径。
Then I added on the edge I need to get there.
然后我添加了需要到达的边缘。
And wherever the shortest path is, it uses some last edge, uv.
无论最短的路径在哪里，它都会使用最后的边缘uv。
There's got to be some choice of u that is the right one.
您必须选择一些正确的选择。
That's the good guess that we're hoping for.
这就是我们所希望的很好的猜测。
We don't know what the good guess
我们不知道有什么好猜测
is so we just try them all.
因此，我们只需尝试所有这些。
But whatever it is, this will be the weight of that path.
但是无论如何，这将是那条路的重担。
It's going to take the best path from s
从s走出最佳路径
to u because sub paths are shortest
到你，因为子路径最短
paths are shortest paths.
路径是最短的路径。
Optimal substructure.
最佳子结构。
So this part will be delta of su.
因此，这部分将是su的增量。
This part is obviously w of uv.
这部分显然是uv的w。
So this will give the right answer.
因此，这将给出正确的答案。
Hopefully.
希望。
OK.
好。
It's certainly going to-- I mean,
这肯定会-我的意思是，
this is the analog of the naive recursive algorithm
这是朴素递归算法的模拟
for Fibonacci.
斐波那契
So it's not going to be efficient if I-- I mean,
因此，如果我-我是说，
this is an algorithm, right?
这是一种算法，对不对？
You could say-- this is a recursive call.
您可以说-这是一个递归调用。
We're going to treat this as recursive call instead
我们将其视为递归调用
of just a definition.
只是一个定义。
Then this is a recursive algorithm.
这是一个递归算法。
How good or bad is this recursive algorithm?
这种递归算法有多好？
AUDIENCE: Terrible.
听众：糟糕。
PROFESSOR: Terrible.
教授：太糟糕了。
Very good.
很好。
Very bad, I should say.
我应该说非常糟糕。
It's definitely going to be exponential
肯定是指数级的
without memoization.
没有记忆。
But we know.
但是我们知道。
We know how to make algorithms better.
我们知道如何使算法更好。
We memoize.
我们记住。
OK.
好。
So I think you know how to write this as a memoized algorithm.
因此，我认为您知道如何将其编写为记忆算法。
To define the function delta of sv, you first check,
要定义sv的函数增量，请先检查，
is s comma v in the memo table?
备注表中的逗号v是？
If so return that value.
如果是这样，则返回该值。
Otherwise, do this computation where this is a recursive call
否则，在这是递归调用的地方进行此计算
and then stored it in the memo table.
然后将其存储在备注表中。
OK.
好。
I don't think I need to write that down.
我认为我不需要写下来。
It's just like the memoized code over there.
就像那边的记忆代码一样。
Just there's now two arguments instead of one.
现在只有两个参数，而不是一个。
In fact, s isn't changing.
实际上，s并没有改变。
So I only need to store with v instead of s comma v.
所以我只需要存储v而不是s逗号v。
Is that a good algorithm?
那是一个好的算法吗？
I claim memoization makes everything faster.
我声称记忆能使一切变得更快。
Is that a fast algorithm?
那是一个快速的算法吗？
Not so obvious, I guess.
我猜不太明显。
Yes?
是？
How many people think, yes, that's a good algorithm?
有多少人认为，这是一个很好的算法？
AUDIENCE: Better.
听众：更好。
PROFESSOR: Better.
教授：更好。
Definitely better.
绝对更好。
Can't be worse.
不会更糟。
How many people think it's a bad algorithm still?
有多少人认为它仍然是一个不好的算法？
OK.
好。
So three for yes, zero for no.
所以三个代表是，零代表否。
How many people aren't sure?
有多少人不确定？
Including the yes votes?
包括赞成票？
Good.
好。
All right.
好吧。
It's not so tricky.
这不是那么棘手。
Let me draw you a graph.
让我给你画一个图。
Something like that.
这样的事情。
So we wanted to commit delta of s comma
所以我们想提交s逗号
v. Let me give these guys names, a and b.
v。让我给这些家伙取名字a和b。
So we compute delta of s comma v. To compute
因此我们计算s逗号v的增量。
that we need to know delta of s comma a and delta
我们需要知道逗号的增量和增量
of s comma v. All right?
s逗号v。好吗？
Those are the two ways-- sorry, actually we just need one.
这是两种方式-抱歉，实际上我们只需要一种。
Only one incoming edge to v. So its delta of s comma a.
v仅有一个输入边。因此，它的逗号间隔为a。
Sorry-- I should have put a base case here too.
抱歉-我也应该在这里放一个基本情况。
Delta of s comma s equals 0.
逗号s的Delta等于0。
OK.
好。
Delta of s comma a plus the edge.
逗号Delta加上边缘。
OK.
好。
There is some shortest path to a.
有一条通往a的最短路径。
To compute the shortest path to a we
要计算到达我们的最短路径
look at all the incoming edges to a.
看一下所有进入的边。
There's only one.
只有一个。
So delta of s comma b.
所以s的逗号是b。
Now I want to compute the shortest paths from b.
现在，我想从b计算最短路径。
Well, there's two ways to get to b.
好吧，有两种方法可以到达b。
One of them is delta of s comma b-- sorry, s comma s.
其中之一是s逗号-抱歉，s逗号。
Came from s.
来自s。
The other way is delta of s comma v. Do you see a problem?
另一种方法是s逗号v的增量。您看到问题了吗？
Yeah.
是的
Delta of s comma v is what we were trying to figure out.
s的Delta逗号是我们试图找出的。
Now you might say, oh, it's OK because we're
现在您可能会说，哦，没关系，因为我们
going to memoize our answer to delta s comma v
要记住我们对delta逗号v的回答
and then we can reuse it here.
然后我们可以在这里重用它。
Except, we haven't finished computing delta of s
除了，我们还没有完成s的增量计算
comma v. We can only put it in the memo table once we're done.
逗号v。完成后，我们只能将其放入备忘表中。
So when this call happens the memo table has not been set.
因此，发生此调用时，尚未设置备忘录表。
And we're going to do the same thing
我们将做同样的事情
over and over and over again.
一而再，再而三。
This is an infinite algorithm.
这是一个无限算法。
Oops.
哎呀。
Not so hot.
不太热。
So it's going to be infinite time on graphs with cycles.
因此，具有周期的图将是无限的时间。
OK.
好。
For DAGs, for acyclic graphs, it actually runs in v plus e time.
对于DAG，对于非循环图，它实际上在v加上e的时间内运行。
This is the good case.
这是很好的情况。
In this situation we can use this formula.
在这种情况下，我们可以使用此公式。
The time is equal to the number of subproblems
时间等于子问题的数量
times the time per subproblem.
乘以每个子问题的时间。
So I guess we have to think about that a little bit.
所以我想我们必须考虑一下。
Where's my code?
我的代码在哪里？
Here's my code.
这是我的代码。
Number of subproblems is v. There's
子问题数是v。
v different subproblems that I'm using here.
v我在这里使用的不同子问题。
I'm always reusing subproblems of the form delta
我一直在重复使用delta形式的子问题
s comma something.
逗号。
The something could be any of the v vertices.
某物可能是v个顶点中的任何一个。
How much time do I spend per subproblem?
每个子问题我要花多少时间？
That's a little tricky.
有点棘手。
It's the number of incoming edges
这是传入边缘的数量
to v. So time for a sub problem delta of sv
v。因此，时间为sv的子问题delta
is the indegree of v. The number of incoming edges to v.
是v的度数。v的传入边数。
So this depends on v. So I can't just
所以这取决于v。所以我不能只是
take a straightforward product here.
在这里拿一个简单的产品。
What this is really saying is, you
这实际上是在说你
should sum up over all sub problems
应该总结所有子问题
of the time per sub problem.
每个子问题的时间。
So total time is the sum over all v and v, the indegree of v.
因此，总时间是所有v和v的总和，即v的度数。
And we know this is number of edges.
我们知道这是边数。
It's really-- so indegree plus 1, indegree plus 1.
的确如此-所以度数加1，度数加1。
So this is v plus v. OK.
这就是v加v。确定。
Handshaking again.
再次握手。
OK.
好。
Now we already knew an algorithm for shortest paths and DAGs.
现在我们已经知道用于最短路径和DAG的算法。
And it ran a v plus e time.
而且它还运行了AV时间。
So it's another way to do the same thing.
因此，这是做同一件事的另一种方法。
If you think about it long enough,
如果您考虑了足够长的时间，
this algorithm memoized, is essentially
记住的这个算法本质上是
doing a depth first search to do a topological sort
进行深度优先搜索以进行拓扑排序
to run one round of Bellman-Ford.
跑一轮贝尔曼福特。
So we had topological sort plus one round of Bellman-Ford.
因此，我们进行了拓扑排序，再加上一轮Bellman-Ford。
This is kind of it all rolled into one.
这全都变成了一种。
This should look kind of like the Bellman Ford relaxation
这看起来有点像贝尔曼福特的放松
step, or shortest paths relaxation step.
步骤或最短路径放松步骤。
It is.
它是。
This min is really doing the same thing.
这个分钟确实在做同样的事情。
So it's really the same algorithm.
因此，它实际上是相同的算法。
But we come at it from a different perspective.
但是我们从不同的角度来看待它。
OK.
好。
But I claim I can use this same approach
但我声称我可以使用相同的方法
to solve shortest paths in general graphs, even when they
解决一般图形中的最短路径，即使它们
have cycles.
有周期。
How am I going to do that?
我该怎么做？
DAGs seem fine-- oh, what was the lesson learned here?
DAG看起来很好-哦，这里学到了什么？
Lesson learned is that subproblem dependencies
吸取的教训是子问题的依赖性
should be acyclic.
应该是非循环的。
Otherwise, we get an infinite algorithm.
否则，我们将得到一个无限算法。
For memoization to work this is what you need.
为了使备忘录有效，这就是您所需要的。
It's all you need.
这就是您所需要的。
OK.
好。
We've almost seen this already.
我们几乎已经看到了这一点。
Because I said that, to do a bottom up algorithm
因为我说过，要做一个自下而上的算法
you do a topological sort of this subproblem dependency DAG.
您对这种子问题依赖项DAG进行了拓扑排序。
I already said it should be acyclic.
我已经说过它应该是非循环的。
OK.
好。
We just forgot.
我们只是忘记了。
I didn't tell you yet.
我还没告诉你
So for that to work it better be acyclic.
因此，要使其正常工作，最好是非循环的。
For DP to work, for memoization to work, it better be acyclic.
为了使DP工作，为了使备忘录工作，最好是非循环的。
If you're acyclic then this is the running time.
如果您是非周期性的，那么这就是运行时间。
So that's all general.
这就是一般。
OK.
好。
So somehow I need to take a cyclic graph
所以我需要做一个循环图
and make it acyclic.
并使其非循环。
We've actually done this already in recitation.
实际上，我们已经在背诵中做到了这一点。
So if I have a graph-- let's take
所以，如果我有一个图表-让我们来
a very simple cyclic graph.
一个非常简单的循环图。
OK.
好。
One thing I could do is explode it into multiple layers.
我可以做的一件事就是将其爆炸成多层。
We did this on quiz two in various forms.
我们以各种形式进行了两次测验。
It's like the only cool thing you can do with shortest paths,
这就像用最短路径可以做的唯一有趣的事情，
I feel like.
我感觉像。
If you want to make a shortest path problem harder,
如果您想使最短路径问题更加困难，
require that you reduce your graph to k copies of the graph.
要求您将图形缩减为k个图形副本。
I'm going to do it in a particular way
我将以一种特殊的方式来做
here-- which I think you've seen in recitation-- which
在这里-我认为您在朗诵中已经看到-
is to think of this axis as time, or however you want,
是将这个轴视为时间，或者您愿意，
and make all of the edges go from each layer
并使所有边缘都来自每一层
to the next layer.
到下一层。
This should be a familiar technique.
这应该是一种熟悉的技术。
So the idea is, every time I follow
所以想法是，每次我跟随
an edge I go down to the next layer.
边缘，我进入了下一层。
This makes any graph acyclic.
这使得任何图都是非循环的。
Done.
做完了
What in the world does this mean?
这到底是什么意思？
What is it doing?
到底在做什么
What does it mean?
这是什么意思？
Double rainbow.
双彩虹。
All right.
好吧。
AUDIENCE: [LAUGHTER]
观众：[笑声]
PROFESSOR: So-- I don't know how I've
教授：所以-我不知道我过得如何
gone so long in the semester without referring
这个学期花了这么长时间没有提到
to double rainbow.
加倍彩虹。
It used to be my favorite.
曾经是我的最爱。
All right.
好吧。
So here's what it means.
这就是它的意思。
Delta sub k of sv.
SV的Delta sub k。
I'm going to define this first-- this
我先定义这个
is a new kind of subproblem-- which
是一种新的子问题-
is, what is the shortest-- what is the weight of the shortest
最短的是什么-最短的重量是多少
s to v path that uses, at most, k edges.
s到v的路径，最多使用k条边。
So I want it to be shortest in terms of total weight,
所以我希望它的总重量最短，
but I also want it to use few edges total.
但我也希望它总共使用很少的边缘。
So this is going to be 0.
所以这将是0。
In some sense, if you look at-- so here's s
从某种意义上讲，如果您看的话-这就是
and I'm always going to make s this.
而且我总是要做到这一点。
And then this is going to be v in the zero situation.
然后在零情况下将为v。
This is going to be v in the one situation,
在一种情况下这将是v
v-- so if I look at this v, I look at the shortest
v--所以如果我看这个v，我看最短的
path from s to v, that is delta sub 0 of sv.
从s到v的路径，即sv的增量sub 0。
So maybe I'll call this v sub 0, v sub 1, v sub 2.
因此，也许我将其称为v sub 0，v sub 1，v sub 2。
OK.
好。
Shortest path from here to here is,
从这里到这里的最短路径是
there's no way to get there on 0 edges.
没有办法在0边到达那里。
Shortest path from here to here, that
从这里到这里的最短路径
is the best way to get there with, at most, one edge.
最多只有一条优势才能到达那里。
Shortest path from here to here--
从这里到这里的最短路径
well, if I add some vertical edges too,
好吧，如果我也添加一些垂直边缘，
I guess, cheating a little bit.
我想，有点作弊。
Then this is the best way to get from s
那么这是从s获得的最好方法
to v using at most two edges.
至v使用最多两个边缘。
And then you get a recurrence which
然后你会复发
is the min over all last edges.
是所有最后一条边的最小值。
So I'm just copying that recurrence,
所以我只是复制那个重复，
but realizing that the s to u part uses one fewer edge.
但意识到从s到u的部分少了一条边。
And then I use the edge uv.
然后，我使用边缘uv。
OK.
好。
That's our new recurrence.
那是我们的新复发。
By adding this k parameter I've made
通过添加这个k参数，我做了
this recurrence on subproblems acyclic.
子问题的这种复发是非周期性的。
Unfortunately, I've increased the number of subproblems.
不幸的是，我增加了子问题的数量。
The number of subproblems now is v squared.
现在，子问题的数量为v平方。
Technically, v times v minus 1.
从技术上讲，v乘以v减去1。
Because I really-- actually, v squared.
因为我真的-实际上，v平方。
Sorry.
抱歉。
I start at 0.
我从0开始。
And what I care about, my goal, is delta sub v minus 1 of sv.
我关心的目标是delta sub v减去sv 1。
Because by Bellman-Ford analysis I
因为通过贝尔曼·福特的分析我
know that I only care about simple paths, paths of length
知道我只关心简单的路径，长度的路径
at most v minus 1.
最多v减1。
I'm assuming here no negative weight cycles.
我假设这里没有负重量循环。
I should've said that earlier.
我应该早一点说。
If you assume that, then this is what I care about.
如果您认为那样，那就是我所关心的。
So k ranges from 0 to v minus 1.
所以k的范围是0到v减去1。
So there are v choices for k.
因此，k有v个选择。
There are v choices for v. So the number of subproblems
v有v个选择。因此，子问题的数量
is v squared.
V平方。
How much time do I spend per subproblem?
每个子问题我要花多少时间？
Well, the same as before.
好吧，和以前一样。
The indegree-- where did I write it?
学位-我在哪里写的？
Up here-- the indegree of that problem.
在这里-该问题的严重性。
So what I'm really doing is summing
所以我真正在做的是总结
over all v of the indegree.
在所有度数上
And then I multiply it by v. So the running time,
然后我将其乘以v。因此运行时间
total running time is ve.
总运行时间为ve。
Sound familiar?
听起来有点熟？
This is Bellman-Ford's algorithm again.
这又是Bellman-Ford的算法。
And this is actually where Bellman-Ford algorithm
这实际上是Bellman-Ford算法的所在
came from is this view on dynamic programming.
来自这种对动态编程的看法。
So we're seeing yet another way to do Bellman-Ford.
因此，我们看到了另一种做Bellman-Ford的方法。
It may seem familiar.
似乎很熟悉。
But in the next three lectures we're
但是在接下来的三讲中
going to see a whole bunch of problems
会看到很多问题
that can succumb to the same approach.
可以屈服于相同的方法。
And that's super cool.
那太酷了。